# Jaime V. Rodriguez

(206) 399-9083 - jaime.v.rodriguez@icloud.com - www.github.com/JaimeVRodriguez - www.jaime-v-rodriguez.com

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **GHOSTMACHINE** (Typescript, React, Java, Springboot, PostgreSQL)

An application leveraging locally hosted AI/ML models, such as Llama3 and Stable Diffusion, to assist Special
Operations Soldiers in generating digital product prototypes for operational use. It provides a suite of tools for prompt
generation, image and voice creation, and text translation, enabling Soldiers to quickly develop and iterate multimedia
content for their missions

#### **DISASTER RESPONSE MAPPING** (Typescript, React, Java, Palantir OSDK)

 Developed during a hackathon hosted by the Army Software Factory and Palantir, this OSDK app supported disaster response efforts by visualizing data on disaster locations using Leaflet. Integrated Palantir-hosted datasets to enable users to locate nearby Army units (with response capabilities) and hospitals (with bed availability) within a specified radius

## **SOLDIER SOLUTIONS** (Typescript, NextJs, TailwindCSS)

• Forward facing website for the Army Software Factory, designed to centralize information about the factory's mission, projects, and career opportunities. Contributed to the refactoring and redesigning of the site, enhancing both the user interface and the overall user experience.

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS: ROLLOUT, BACKTRACK, SPECIAL OPERATIONS RECRUITING ANALYSIS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer US Army Special Operations

July 2023 – Present

- Spearheaded the transition of a test-phase application to an operational environment, increasing user adoption from 0 to 6 operational users by collaborating with stakeholders and incorporating user feedback to enhance functionality and usability.
- Directed the organization's education portfolio, achieving a 450% increase in education and intern pipeline participation (from 2 to 11 participants) in the inaugural class and developing a 12-month strategic plan, including hosting hackathons and delivering in-house courses.

Data Analyst

US Army Special Operations

August 2022 – July 2023

- Delivered actionable insights by analyzing GDELT data, enabling the senior data scientist to guide strategies, which directly influenced commanders' operational decision-making.
- Collaborated with the software development team to design and integrate an analytics dashboard into the team's
  application, providing commanders with real-time, data-driven insights to enhance situational awareness and
  decision-making.

Special Operations Recruiter (Talent Acquisition Specialist)

US Army Special Operations

July 2019 – August 2022

- Assisted in the planning, creation, and deployment of the organizations' first virtual recruiting team utilizing social media and other digital platforms resulting in an increase of 148% leads generated.
- Mentored N.C. State Graduate students in the development of a minimal viable product for a recommender system software solution to be utilized by recruiters across the Special Operations Recruiting organization.

Psychological Operations Team Lead (Market Research Team Lead) US Army Special Operations

October 2017 – June 2019

### **EDUCATION**

EASTERN UNIVERSITY BELLEVUE UNIVERSITY

Master of Science in Data Science, December 2024 – GPA: 4.0 Bachelor of Science in Software Development, May 2021 – GPA: 3.978